Guide to the Janet Lewis Papers, 1964-1989
Department of Special Collections
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Lewis, Katherine. 1 ALS, Aug. 8, [1983].Includes 1 photo.
  - Library of Congress. Correspondence, Sept. 1968 to May 1980. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Lieberman, Morton W. 1 ALS, March 25, 1977.
  - Light, Erica. 1 ALS, Dec. 28, 1981.
  - Lilibridge, Tom & Diane. 1 birth announcement, Sept. 1 [n.y.].
  - Limmer, Ruth. 1 TLS, March 28, 1971.
  - Little Magazine, The. 1 printed CS, [n.d.].
  - Lockett, Rowena. 1 ALS, Feb. 6, 1984.
  - Loftis, Mr. and Mrs. John Clyde. 1 wedding invitation, Dec. 27, 1969.
  - Loomis, Ed. 1 TLS, April 9, 1971.Includes 1 carbon TL from Janet Lewis Winters.
  - Lougee, Carolyn C. 1 TLS, Feb. 4, 1982. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lowell, Susan. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, July 10, [1969]; [n.d.].
  - Luce, Gay. 1 TLS, [Oct. 20, 1968].
  - Lyman, Ying. Correspondence, Aug. 1980 to June 1981.
  - Lynn, Kenneth S. 1 TLS, Jan. 27, 1983.
  - Lyon, Geoffrey. Correspondence, [Feb. 1964] to March 1964.
  - MacArthur Foundation. 1 TLS, [Aug. 3, 1981].Includes 1 brochure. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - McCarter, James D. 1 ALS, Nov. 23, 1978.
  - McClure, Charlotte. 2 TLS, April 11, 1977; July 5, 1977.
  - McCullough, Frances. 1 TLS, July 18, 1978.
  - McDowell, Frederick P.W. 1 TLS, Jan. 9, 1982.
  - McGregor, Jean. 1 ALS, July 14, 1977.
  - McLaughlin, Ann. Correspondence, Oct. 1967 to Feb. 1979.Includes introductory comments for a workshop on Transmuting Personal Experience into Fiction, with mention and participation of Janet Lewis Winters.
  - -----. Correspondence et al., [May 1979] to July 1983.Includes reviews of The Return of Martin Guerre. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - McLaughlin, Charles. 1 TLS et al., Feb. 24, 1980.
  - Macmillan Administration Ltd. 1 TLS et al., March 11, 1980.Manlay, Beatrice. Correspondence et al., Dec. 1970 to [April 1983]. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Marquis Biographical Library Society, The. Announcement of Janet Lewis Winters' membership, [n.d.].
  - Marsden, Michael T. 1 TLS, April 4, 1971.
  - Matrix Press. 1 TLS, March 21, 1980.Included photocopy and proof copy of The Indians in the Woods by Janet Lewis Winters. Manuscript transferred to Box 8, folder 1. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - May Massee Memorial Fund. 2 TLS, Dec. 1, 1969; Feb. 12, 1970. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Meadow Press. 1 ALS et al., Feb. 11, [n.y.].Includes proof copy of poem Betatakin First Seen, Autumn. Manuscript transferred to Box 8, folder 1.
  - Mears, Gladys. 1 ALS, Feb. 15, [n.y.].
  - Meem, Faith. Correspondence, Nov. 1968 to Oct. [1983][no pm after this date].
  - Meem, John. Correspondence, June 1976 to [Aug. 1979].
  - Mendelowitz, Mildred. 1 C, Jan. 25, 1983. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Merritt, Herb. 1 ALS, Dec. 5, 1979.
  - Meyers, Jeffrey. 1 TLS, Jan. 23, 1983.
  - Michaels, Barbara L. 1 TLS, Aug. 8, 1978.
  - Mialle, M. et Mme. Jean. 1 wedding invitation, July 6, 1968.
  - Middlebrook, Diane. 1 TLS, Feb. 11, 1981.
  - Miles, Jo. Correspondence, [Feb. 1964] to [1983].
  - Miller, Greg. Correspondence, [n.d.] to Dec. 1983.
  - Miller, Louisa, 1 ALS, Jan. 27, 1980.
  - Mills College. 1 ALS, Dec. 14, 1979. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Mintz, Sylvia. Correspondence et al., Nov. [1969] to [1975].
  - Minorsky, Magdelaine. 1 ACS, [n.d.].
  - Mogulescu, Miles. 2 TLS, Dec. 26, 1980; Jan. 19, 1981. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Molnar, Maria. 1 TLS, April 4, 1981.
  - Momaday, Al. 1 ALS, Nov. 30, 1971.
  - Momaday, Natachee Scott. Correspondence et al., March 1964 to March 1969.
  - -----. Correspondence et al., May 1969 to June 1982.Includes 1 photo, 1 poem Abstract: Old Woman in a Room, text The Centaur Complex, 1 drawing. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Montague, Clarence. 1 TLS, Jan. 9, 1965.
  - Morales, Manuel. 2 ALS, April 1970 to [n.d.] 1970.
  - Morris, Cecile. 2 ALS, Feb. 28, 1979; May 14, 1981.
  - Morris, Wright. Correspondence, Jan. 15, [1975] to Oct. 1981[no pm after this date].
  - Mount St. Scholastica College. 2 ALS, Aug. 30, 1968; Oct. 19, 1968. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Murphy, Frank. Correspondence, June 1971 to April 1977[no pm after this date].
  - Murray, Bain. Correspondence et al., May 1976 to June 1981.
  - -----. Correspondence et al., July 1981 to Aug. 1982.Includes 1 photo, also reviews of performances, by Bain Murray, of compositions set to the poetry (The Lewis Triptych) of Janet Lewis Winters; also A Vision of Immortality. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1983 to Oct. 1983. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Murray, Fran. Correspondence, Aug. 1964 to Aug. 1976 and [n.d.]. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Musham, Liela. 1 ALS, July 15, [1976]. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Napier, Julia. 1 ALS, Feb. 1, 1980.
  - Nash, Edith. Correspondence, Dec. 1981 to July 1982.
  - Navajo Community College. 2 TLS, Sept. 19, 1977; Oct. 17, 1977.
  - Netreba, Laurie. 1 ALS, Aug. 17, 1980.
  - Nelson, Gisela. 1 ALS, April 23, 1968.
  - Neumann, Faith. Correspondence, [n.d.].
  - New Directions. Correspondence, royalty statements et al., Sept. 1969 to June 1970.Includes 2 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters and other correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - -----. Correspondence, June 1970 to Jan. 1971.Includes 2 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters and other correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements et al., Jan. 1971 to March 1971.Includes 4 carbon TL, 1 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters and other correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - -----. Correspondence, royality statements, May 1971 to Nov. 1971. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements et al., June 1981 to Nov. 1982. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New Republic, The. Correspondence, Sept. 1979 to Aug. 1980.Includes poem In a Convalescent Hospital. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - New York Review of Books, The. 1 TLS, May 7, 1964.
  - No Deadlines. Correspondence, Dec. 1978 to Feb. 1980.
  - Norman, Emile. 1 printed card with note, [Oct. 17, 1979].
  - Novak, Paul. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, Sept. 19, 1975; Oct. 16, 1975.
  - [Nutauer, --?]. 1 ALS et al., [n.d.].
  - Odell, Jo Ann. 1 ALS, July 12, 1978. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Oehlmann, Hil. 1 ALS, Dec. 14, [n.y.].
  - Ohio Review. Correspondence et al., Sept. 1975 to March 1983.
  - Olive, May Anne. 1 ALS, March 16, 1979.
  - Oregon Shakespeare Festival Association. 1 TLS, Aug. 9, 1969.
  - Ornell, Robert Whaley. 2 TLS, July 8, 1977; Aug. 29, 1978.
  - Osborn, Stellanova. Correspondence et al., [n.d.] to Dec. 1982.
  - Outlook. 1 TLS, Oct. 28, 1975.
  - Pace, Jean. 1 ALS, Feb. 26, [n.y.]. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pace, Zietta. 1 ALS, Aug. 26, 1960.
  - Packer, Nancy. 1 ALS, Sept. 27. [1975].
  - Palo Alto Senior High School, Creative Writing Class. 1 poem Thank you, Janet Lewis Winters, Oct. 1974.
  - Palo Alto Unified School District. Correspondence et al., [n.d.] to Oct. 1968.
  - Parkinson, Thomas. Correspondence et al., April 1975 to May 1975.Includes review of the Crane-Winters letters.
  - Parnie, Elaine. 1 ALS, Jan. 28, 1971.
  - Patterson, Kelsey. 1 ALS, June 1, 1975.
  - Pellegrin, Helen. 1 ACS, [n.d.].
  - P.E.N. American Center. Correspondence et al., March 1977 and before to May 1983 and after. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Penguin Books, Ltd. Correspondence, royalty statements, Sept. 1972 to July 1978.
  - Permaen Press. 1 TLS, [Feb. 28, 1980].Includes 2 proof copies of poem Geometries: North Studio, Yaddo. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Perivale Press. 1 ALS, 1 ACS et al., Feb. 23, 1983; March 9, 1983.
  - Perlmutter, Elizabeth [later Elizabeth Frank]. Correspondence, Dec. 1975 to April 1981.
  - Pesic, Peter. Correspondence et al., Aug. 1976 to Oct. 1983.Includes poem The Shaman's Farewell by Peter Pesic. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Pindar, Sally. 2 ALS, [Aug. 11, 1975]; [n.d.].
  - Pinsky, Robert. Correspondence, June 1979 to Jan. 1983.
  - Poetry. 1 TLS, Aug. 4, 1977.
  - Poetry Center, The. 1 TLS et al., Dec. 17, 1981. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Portable Stanford, The. 2 TLS, both May 20, 1980.Includes other correspondence.
  - Powell, Grove. Correspondence et al., June 1976 to Dec. 1983.
  - Pressly, Karen and Bill. 1 TLS, Oct. 26, [1976]. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Ptaszynska, Marte. 1 ALS, June 9, 1975.
  - Quinn, Alice. Correspondence et al., April [n.y.] to Dec. [n.y.].Includes 1 copy of Elsewhere, a story by Elizabeth Bishop.
  - Radius, Nancy. 2 ALS et al., [Aug. 7, 1980]; Sept. 28, 1980.
  - Ramsey, Henry. Correspondence et al., [Aug. 1971] to June 1983.Includes reviews of The Return of Martin Guerre and 1 announcement of Nathalie Zemon Davis' book with the same title.
  - Rapp & Whiting. 1 telegram, [May 24, 1968].
  - Rasso, Pamela S. 1 TLS, Aug. 7, 1979. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rawles. Teresa. 1 ALS, July 26, [1971].
  - Readers Digest. 1 telegram, Dec. 16, [n.y.].
  - Reaven, Eve. 1 ALS, [1980].
  - Resource Center for Women. 1 TLS, May 5, 1983.
  - Riggs, Janet. 1 ALS, Jan. 8, 1976.
  - Rippin, Charles. 2 ALS, Sept. 27, 1981; March 21, 1983.
  - Robin, Robert S. 2 TLS, Sept. 5, 1967; Sept. 7, 1967.
  - Robinson, David B. 2 TLS, July 20, 1978; Aug. 1, 1981.
  - Rodriguez, Suzanne. 1 TLS, Nov. 4, 1980.
  - Rood, Linda. Correspondence et al., Aug. 1976 to Oct. 1981. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Rosenfels, Marscia. 1 ALS, June 19, [1976].
  - Rosener, Ann. 1 TLS, Oct. 11, [1982].
  - Rosenthal, David Bruce. 1 marriage announcement, Dec. 2, 1971.
  - Rosenthal, Jonathan M. 1 marriage announcement, Aug. 10, 1979.
  - Roskam, Jo. 1 note, 1 ALS, July 10, [1978]; Oct. 2, [1978].
  - Roth, Bill. 1 TLS, April 23, [1983].
  - Routledge & Kegan Paul, Ltd. 1 TLS, [March 8, 1970].
  - Retired Senior Volunteer Program. 1 TLS, June 5, 1979.
  - Rungstedlund Foundation, The. 1 TLS, Jan. 30, 1980.
  - Russell, Elizabeth. 1 TLS, [March 5, 1970].
  - Russell, Ernest F. 1 ALS, March [2, 1977].
  - Russell, Peggy. 1 ALS, July 15, 1975.
  - Ryan, Michael. 1 ALS, 1 TLS, Nov. 19, 1982; [n.d.].Includes photocopies of photographs of Yvor Winters. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Saint Catharine College. 1 TLS, Oct. 14, 1981.
  - Saint John's College. 1 TLS, Aug. 14, 1980.
  - Salvi-Crestiani, Mildred. 2 ALS, July 22, 1972; July 10/12, [1973].
  - Samuel, Sister. 1 ALS, [Feb. 7, 1978].
  - San Jose Poetry Center. 1 TLS et al., Sept. 30, 1982.
  - Sayre, Arthur. Correspondence et al., Oct. 1967 to June 1970.Includes other correspondence.
  - Scarecrow Press. 1 TLS, May 9, 1983. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Schmidt, Harold. 1 ALS, Nov. 20, [n.y.].
  - Schmidt, Michael. Correspondence, Feb. 1977 to Sept. 1978.
  - Schmidt, Stephen. Correspondence et al., Aug. 1969 to May 1970.
  - Seagle, Helen. Correspondence. Oct. [1977] to Oct. 1979.
  - Seagrave, Malcolm. Correspondence, Dec. 1977 to Sept. 1981.
  - Seamstern, Fannie. 1 ALS, Aug. 2, 1971.
  - Serendipity Books. Correspondence, [July 1975] to [Dec. 1977].
  - Sheikh, Vangie and Yusuf. 1 TLS, March 24, 1969.
  - Sherry, Pearl. Correspondence, Feb. 1975 to June 1983.Includes other correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., June 1983 to Dec. [n.y.].Includes Some Thoughts about Symbolism. Also a Few Excerpts on Technique from the Letters of Elizabeth Madox Roberts. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Silvers, [Eva]. 1 ALS, May 16, 1967.
  - Simon, Marc. 1 ALS, March 9, 1976.
  - Simone, Carol. Correspondence et al., Dec. 1978 to Nov. 1979.Includes poems Helen Grown Old, Remembered Morning.
  - Simpson, Claude. 1 ALS et al., Feb. 7, 1976.Includes other correspondence. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Simpson, Mrs. Claude. 1 ALS, [April 26, 1976].
  - Simpson, Gail. 1 ALS, [Feb. 24, 1981].
  - Slavick, Bill. Correspondence, Feb. 1979 to May 1983.Includes 1 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters and other correspondence.
  - Smitter, Lily. 2 ALS, March 21, 1979; April 25, 1980. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Southern Review, The. 2 TLS, March 5, 1978; June 25, 1982.
  - Southwood, Mrs. Eric. 1 TLS, Feb. 1, 1979.
  - Spangenberg, Mrs. Karl R. 1 wedding invitation, [Feb. 25, 1979].
  - Spear, Roberta. Correspondence et al., Dec. 1975 to Aug. 1983.Includes a review of The Return of Martin Guerre and an account of Janet Lewis' Eightieth-Birthday Celebration in the Newsletter of the English Department at Stanford.
  - Speare, Woodridge. Correspondence, Aug. 1975 to May 1982.Includes Toward In the Great Steep's Garden and Chicago, an essay about Elizabeth Madox Roberts.
  - Stafford, Clayton. 2 ALS, Dec. 10, [1969]; Dec. 26, 1969.Includes 1 marriage announcement. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Stafford, Ruth. 2 ALS, June 30, 1981; July 30, 1982.
  - Stanford, Ann. Correspondence et al., July 1971 to April 1982.
  - Stanford, Donald. Correspondence, Dec. 1968 to April 1978.Includes other correspondence.
  - -----. Correspondence et al., May 1978 to Jan. 1980.Includes a review of the Crane-Winters correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1980 to April 1982. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stanford, Maryanna. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1977 to March 1977. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Alumni Association. 1 TLS et al., June 7, 1977.Includes 1 ph. AS account of the Navajo-Hopi Land Expedition and other correspondence.
  - Stanford University - C.R.O.W. (Center for Research on Women). Correspondence et al., Nov. 1971 to April 1982. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Stanford University Libraries. Correspondence et al., Sept. 1968 to Feb. 1982. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., March 1982 to Nov. 1983.Includes other correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Stanford University. 1 TLS, Sept. 19, 1983. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University, Office of the President. Correspondence, June 1968 to Sept. 1983.
  - Stanford Women's Club of San Francisco. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, Jan. 4, 1964; March 9, [n.y.].
  - State University of New York at Albany. 1 TLS, April 9, 1982.
  - Steele, Tim. Correspondence et al., [Nov. 1974] to May 1983.Includes an article Writer's Choice: A Library of Rediscoveries with mention of Janet Lewis Winters.
  - Steffey, Mrs. Carl. 1 ALS, Sept. 3, 1965.
  - Steiger, Kitty Bell. 1 ALS, Jan. 18, [n.y.].
  - Stephen, Sister Ellen. 1 ALS, Sept. 19, 1972. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Stewart, Ken. 1 ALS, May 27, [1975].
  - Stokes, Donald. 1 TLS, Feb. 6, 1979.Includes an interview with Janet Lewis Winters.
  - Stone, Naomi Burton. 1 TLS, 1 TCS, Sept. 10, 1970; Sept. 27, 1970.
  - Strum, Ione. Correspondence, Jan. 1970 to March 1983[no pm after this date].
  - Sullivan, Khoan. Correspondence, July 1976 to Oct. 1983. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Swallow, Alan. 1 agreement et al., [Aug. 28, 1967].Includes 1 ph. TLS by Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Swallow Press, The, Inc. Correspondence and royalty statements, Dec. 1967 to Nov. 1968.
  - -----. Correspondence et al. Dec. 1968 to Sept. 1969.Includes 1 carbon TL and 1 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters, 1 review article with mention of Janet Lewis Winters, and other correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, Sept. 1969 to Dec. 1969.Includes a short review/announcement of The Wife of Martin Guerre and 2 carbon TL from Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, Dec. 1969 to Jan. 1970.Includes 3 TL from Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, brochures, Feb. 1970 to Oct. 1970[no pm after this date]. Includes 1 carbon TLS and 1 ph. TL from Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - -----. Royalties, Nov. 1970 to Oct. 1974.Includes other correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, March 1975 to Aug. 1976. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, Feb. 1977 to Jan. 1979.Includes other correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, Feb. 1979 to Aug. 1980.Includes 1 carbon TL from Janet Lewis Winters and other correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, Sept. 1980 to July 1981.Includes 1 carbon TL from Janet Lewis Winters and a review of her Poems Old and New. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, copyright material, July 1981 to Dec. 1981.Includes other correspondence. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - -----. Correspondence, Oct. 1982 to Jan. 1983.Includes excerpts of the proof copies of Yvor Winters' essays on Moby Dick and John Crowe Ransom and other correspondence. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, Feb. 1983 to Oct. 1983.Includes other correspondence. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - -----. Correspondence, contract assignment, Dec. 1983 to [n.d.]. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tana, Tomal. Correspondence, [May 1970] to Oct. 1983.Includes poems For Mrs. Tana. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Tarantino, Mardijah. Correspondence, [Oct. 1976] to April 1980.
  - Tarshis, [?] & Lorie. 1 ALS, Dec. 8, 1970.
  - Taylor, Irene. 1 ALS, June 18, 1971.
  - Thieriot, Bob. 1 wedding invitation et al., 1 ALS, Dec. 20, [1969]; Dec. 2, [n.y.]. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Thieriot, Janet. 1 ALS, June 2, 1982.
  - Thieriot, Peggy. 1 ALS, Feb. 14, 1977.
  - Thompson, Don. Correspondence et al., [May 1975] to Jan. 1980.
  - Thompson, Eric & Florence. Correspondence, Jan. 1965 to Oct. 1975[no pm after this date].
  - Thompson, Joanna, Sara, & Michael. Correspondence, March [1974] to June [n.y.]. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Thompson, Michael. Birthday and other drawings, [n.d.].
  - Thompson, Sara. Correspondence, [May 1974] to Jan. 1983.
  - Thomson, Sedgefield. 1 ALS, [n.d.].
  - Thonieson, James. 1 TLS, Oct. 4, 1983.
  - Thorpe, Connie. 1 ALS, July 26, [n.y.]. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Threepenny Review, The. Correspondence, Oct. 1979 to July [n.y.].
  - Toigo, Helen. Correspondence, [June 1975] to [n.d.].
  - Toigo, John. Correspondence et al., May [1969] to May 1975.Includes 1 ph. ALS from Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Tooker, Dan. Correspondence et al., Oct. 1975 to April [1976].
  - Transition. 1 ACS, Jan. 21, 1983. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - TriQuarterly. Correspondence, Sept. 1981 to Nov. 1982.
  - Trusky, Tom. 1 ATS, April 21, 1978.
  - Turpin, Mildred & Sally Pindar. Correspondence, July 1967 to [n.d.].
  - University of California, Berkeley. Correspondence et al., March 1978 to June [1980].
  - University of Chicago, Alumni Association. 2 TLS et al., Feb. 12, 1982; March 16, 1982. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - University of Chicago Library. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1981 to Sept. 1982.
  - University of Wisconsin. Correspondence et al., June 1967 to Jan. 1970[no pm after this date]. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Valdes, Joan. Correspondence et al., Sept. 1975 to [n.d.].Includes an article on Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - [Van Den...?], Peter. 1 ALS, Oct. 8, 1977.
  - Viking Press. Correspondence, Oct. 1938 [sic] to April 1969.
  - Van Hallberg, Robert. 1 TLS, Sept. 15, 1980.
  - Virginia Commomwealth University. 1 TLS, May 1979.
  - W.W. Norton Co., Inc. Correspondence, March 1965 to Nov. 1968.Includes other correspondence. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Wagner, Isabel. 1 ALS et al., [Feb. 5, 1975].
  - Wald, Alan. 1 TLS, July 24, 1976.
  - Walkup, Kathy. Correspondence, [Jan. 1980] to May [1981].
  - Wallace, Peter. 1 ALS, May 23, 1976. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Wallace Stevens Journal, The. 2 TLS, July 28, 1979; Feb. 16, 1979.Includes 1 carbon TL by Janet Lewis Winters.
  - Wallace-Taylor, Audrey. Correspondence, June [1978] to Jan. 1980.Includes a proof copy of Reading for Yade Skagsberg.
  - -----. Correspondence et al., [May 1980] to Nov. [n.y.]. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Walzer, Sady. 1 ALS, Aug. 22, 1979.
  - Ward, Joan S. 1 ALS, April 8, 1983.
  - Watt, Ian. 1 ALS, March 18, 1981.
  - Webb, Peggy. Correspondence, Dec. 1978 to Dec. 1980.
  - Weisman, Morton P. 1 TLS, June 2, 1982. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - West, Jessamyn. 1 ALS, Oct. 30, 1977.
  - Weston, Joy. Correspondence, May [1973] to Sept. 1975[no pm after this date].
  - Weygers, Alexander G. 1 ACS, [July 20, (n.y.)].
  - Wheelock, Sara (& Sally Pindar). Correspondence, [Aug. 1978] to Oct. 1983.
  - Who's Who in America. 1 galley proof, [n.d.]. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Williams, Ellea. 1 TLS, March 26, 1975.
  - Wilmington Opera Society. 1 TLS, Sept. 1, 1976.
  - Winters, Melissa. Correspondence et al., [Feb. 1980] to [n.d.].
  - Winters, Nancy. Correspondence, [June 1975] to Aug. [1983].
  - Wirth, Nancy. Correspondence, Jan. [1977] to Dec. [n.y.].
  - Wohlfort, Bill. 1 wedding invitation, June 27, 1970. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Wolcott, Anne. Correspondence, May 1967 to Dec. 1982.Includes 1 photo.
  - Wolcott, Peter C. 1 TLS, Dec. 8, [1967].
  - Wolman, Cecil. Correspondence, Sept. 1962 to Feb. 1983.Includes poem Winter Canyon. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Woods, Marie. 1 TLS, July 12, 1974. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Wright, Anne. 1 TLS, Nov. 17, 1978.
  - Wright, Celeste. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1981 to July 1983.Includes sonnets Again the Forest Road and a review of The Return of Martin Guerre.
  - Yaddo. Correspondence, May 1976 to [n.d.].Includes print of poem Geometries, North Studio at Yaddo. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Yale University, Audio Visual Center. 1 TLS [to Mr. Winters], royalty statements, Oct. 8, 1968.
  - Yankee, Inc. 1 TLS et al., March 22, 1979. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Young, Jim & Meg. 1 birth announcement, 1 ALS, [Jan. 20, 1982], [Feb. 8, 1982].
  - Yueh, Norma. 1 TLS, Aug. 17, 1967.
  - Zelditch, Bernice. Correspondence et al., April 1971 to Aug. 1971.Includes 1 duplicate TLS from Janet Lewis Winters, a review wiwth mention of Yvor Winters' poetry and other correspondence.
- Manuscripts by Janet Lewis Winters
  - photocopy of a typescript by Janet Lewis Winters about Katherine Anne Porter, [n.d.].Poem, For Louise, regarding Louise Chenery transferred from Box 1, folder 23. Proof copy of The Indians in the Woods transferred from Box 4, folder 15. Proof copy of Betatakin First Seen, Autumn transferred from Box 4, folder 16., Calendar, April, 1989. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Miscellanea by Janet Lewis Winters
  - Letters, notes, lists, addresses, etc. by Janet Lewis Winters, Jan. [1966] and before to Jan. 1981 [and after?].Includes Christmas greeting cards of the Lewis family dating from 1916, 1917, 1920,and 1 ph. of poem A Lullaby by Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Manuscripts by others
  - Poem by Janet's father, 6/2/05. (Box 8, Folder 3.)
  - Poem by Margaret Henrichsen, 6/26/25. (Box 8, Folder 4.)
- Reviews of Janet Lewis Winter's works
  - 1 ph. review of Good-bye, Son, April 14, 1946.Reviews of Poems Old and New: 1918 - 1978, April 1981 to Sept. 1982.Carbon typescript of a review of The Wife of Martin Guerre by Evan Connell transferred from Box 2, folder 3. (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Miscellaneous items sent to Janet Lewis Winters
  - Flyers, invoices, book lists, announcements, programs, etc. Includes an article Janet Lewis: `To bind despair and joy Into a stable whole.' by Joan Valdes and a preview of The Return of Martin Guerre. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Photographs